+1 3417326710
Fort Collins, CO
himanshu.soni@colostate.edu

Himanshu Soni

linkedin.com/in/HiSoni09 github.com/HiSoni09 www.cs.colostate.edu/~himansh0/

Software Engineer/Web/Full Stack/React/NodeJS with 3.5 years of experience. Involved right from Requirement gathering, System Design, Development, Integration, Testing, Deployment, and Product support. Passionate about new technologies, different and more effective ways of handling regular tasks. Believes in Test/Behavior Driven Development. Excellent written and verbal communication skills.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Programming: ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Redux, Saga, CSS, HTML, Java
- Other: Docker, Webpack, WordPress, Git, Sonar, OOPS, SASS, LESS, Python, Oracle, media query
- Database: MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB
- UI Library: Bootstrap 4, Material UI, Ant Design
- Unit Test Framework: Jest, Enzyme
- Api Testing Tool: Postman, Swagger

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO

Post-Graduation Diploma in Advanced Computing

CDAC Knowledge Park, Bangalore, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering

Maharshi Dayanand University, Rohtak, India

Expected May 2024

Feb 2019

May 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Corporate Webmaster

Nov 2022 - Current

Jun 2021 - Jul 2022

Rocky Mountain Student Media Corp., CSU, Fort Collins, CO, USA

- Responsible for the content and reliability of 6 media outlet websites that have over 1.5 million visitors per year.
- Gathering requirements for features or change-request followed by analysis and business proposal.
- Doing SEO changes and Google Analytics to improve the website's performance and revenue.

Software Engineer

William O'Neil India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India

- Created single-page responsive web applications using ReactJs, Redux, and Redux Saga.
- Migrated Java services to NodeJS.
- Responsible for programming UI, API, bug fixing, SEO changes, deployment, and integration.
- Experience designing and architecting front-end apps from the ground up.
- Resolved high-priority customer tickets and bugs while ensuring minimum turnaround time.
- Mentored intern and performed code review.

Software Engineer

Mar 2019 - Jun 2021

Happiest Minds Technologies Ltd., Bangalore, India

- Designed and implemented dynamic web pages using React hooks and class base components.
- Worked on routing and authentication using JWT, local, and session storage.
- Worked on Jest unit test cases.
- Experience designing Nodejs REST APIs that are clear and easy to consume.
- Created cross-browser and platform-independent CSS using media query.

RECENT RELEVANT PROJECT

MarketSmith

Jul 2021 - Feb 2022

This is one of the stock analysis tools of William O'Neil where users can do stocks trading. Working as a Module Lead my responsibilities were to integrate TradingView and Drivewealth trading libraries, and creating web pages using ReactJS, NodeJS, Vanilla JavaScript, and Java Server Page. Other tasks were testing, deploying, integration, bug fixes, etc.